National Congress of Neighborhood Women Records, 1974-1999
Sophia Smith Collection, Smith College
- SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS 1974-1991
  - Jewel Street Neighbors Block Association: correspondence and printed material, 1981 (Box 132, Folder 4)
  - Learning Alliance - Options for Education and Action: meetings, 1986 (Box 132, Folder 5)
    [See also SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION-Individuals -Lisel Burns]
  - Lutheran Settlement House: brochures, correspondence, reports, and printed material, circa 1978-86 (Box 132, Folder 6)
  - Manhattan Coalition of Area Policy Boards: printed material, 1980-81 (Box 132, Folder 7)
    [See also Williamsburg-Greenpoint Community Planning Board No. 1]
  - Mass Transit Street Theater: correspondence, 1985 (Box 132, Folder 8)
  - Mayor's Task Force on Rape: articles, brochures, correspondence, meetings, notes, and printed material, 1974-79 (Box 132, Folder 9)
    [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Women's Survival Center]
  - Mountain Women's Exchange: correspondence, and printed material, 1984-86 (Box 132, Folder 10)
  - Ms. "Decade of Women": printed material, 1979 (Box 132, Folder 11)
  - National Advisory Committee on Women (for National Women's Conference, Houston, 1977): correspondence and report, 1978 (Box 132, Folder 12)
    [See also National Women's Conference Committee]
  - National Alliance of Community Based Organizations (NACBO): brochure, 1981 (Box 132, Folder 13)
  - National Association of Neighborhoods: 1977-83
    - General: correspondence, meeting notes and minutes, newsletters, proposals, reports, speeches, and printed material, 1977-83, undated (Box 133, Folder 1-4)
    - 5th National Conference, Pittsburgh: notes, resolutions, and printed material, Apr. 1977 (Box 133, Folder 5)
    - 6th National Conference, Chicago: correspondence, meeting notes, reports, proposals, and printed material, October 1977 (Box 133, Folder 6)
    - Women's Caucus: correspondence, news article, and notes, 1980 (Box 133, Folder 7)
    - National Displacement Committee: correspondence and printed material, 1980 (Box 133, Folder 8)
    - Financial: budgets, correspondence, and printed material (Box 133, Folder 9)
    - Mailing lists (Box 133, Folder 10)
    - Bulletins, 1977-80 (Box 133, Folder 11)
  - National Association of Social Workers: correspondence and printed material, 1981 (Box 134, Folder 1)
  - National Center for Neighborhood Enterprise: correspondence, 1986 (Box 134, Folder 2)
  - National Center for Urban Ethnic Affairs: correspondence, 1978 (Box 134, Folder 3)
  - National Citizen's Coalition for the Windfall Profits Tax: correspondence, undated (Box 134, Folder 4)
  - National Coalition of Organizations Committed to Neighborhoods: minutes, 1979 (Box 134, Folder 5)
  - National Commission on Neighborhoods: correspondence, drafts, papers, and printed material, 1977-78, undated (Box 134, Folder 6)
  - National Committee on United States-China Relations, Inc.: printed material, 1979 (Box 134, Folder 7)
  - "National Conference for Developing Local Private-Public Enterprises": correspondence and printed material, 1978 (Box 134, Folder 8)
  - "National Conference on Citizen Participation," 1983-84 (Box 134, Folder 9-10)
  - National Consultation on Economic Justice for Women Who Are Poor": newsletters, notes, and printed material, 1983-85 (Box 134, Folder 11)
  - National Council for Research on Women: printed material, undated (Box 134, Folder 12)
  - National Forum on the Black Family, "From Our Strengths": report, 1986 (Box 134, Folder 13)
  - National Hispanic Women's Network: directory, 1982 (Box 134, Folder 14)
  - National Italian American Foundation: correspondence, 1978 (Box 134, Folder 15)
  - National Low Income Housing Coalition: correspondence, newsletters, photograph, and printed material, 1978-80, undated (Box 134, Folder 16)
  - National Neighborhood Coalition: agenda, correspondence, clippings, notes, proposals, and printed material, 1979-86 (Box 134, Folder 17)
  - National Organization for Women: correspondence and flyers, 1979, undated (Box 134, Folder 18)
    [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment-P.O.D.]
  - The National Urban Coalition: news article, 1986 (Box 134, Folder 19)
  - National Women's Agenda Coalition (Women's Action Alliance): budgets, meeting notes, and papers, 1976-77 (Box 134, Folder 20)
  - National Women's Conference Committee, 1977-87 (Box 135, Folder 1-2)
    [See also National Advisory Committee]
  - National Women's Political Caucus: correspondence, newsletter, and printed material, 1985-87, undated (Box 135, Folder 3)
  - Neighborhoods and Communities Political Action Committee: correspondence and printed material, 1984, undated (Box 135, Folder 4)
  - Network, The Monthly for Utah's Working Women: newspaper, 1979 (Box 135, Folder 5)
  - New Jersey State Division on Women: brochures, correspondence, and printed material, 1985-87, undated (Box 135, Folder 6)
  - New York City Commission on the Status of Women: correspondence, flyers, newsletters, notes, programs, reports, and printed material, 1977-85 (Box 135, Folder 7)
  - New York Feminist Federal Credit Union: minutes, 1977 (Box 135, Folder 8)
    [See also SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment- POD]
  - New York Network: correspondence and printed material, 1983 (Box 135, Folder 9)
  - New York State Campaign for Abortion Rights: brochures, notes, and printed material, 1981-82, undated (Box 135, Folder 10)
  - New York State Division for Women: correspondence, 1984 (Box 135, Folder 11)
  - New York State Task Force on Women's Issues: report, 1984 (Box 135, Folder 12)
  - New York State Tenant and Neighborhood Coalition: correspondence and article 1989 (Box 135, Folder 13)
  - New York Women's Coalition: minutes, notes, and survey, 1977, undated (Box 135, Folder 14)
    [See also Women's Funding Coalition; and SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment-P.O.D.]
  - North Brooklyn Arts Council: flyers, program, and printed material, 1981, undated (Box 135, Folder 15)
  - Not In Our Name: flyer, 1984 (Box 135, Folder 16)
  - Ohio Women, Inc.: printed material, undated (Box 135, Folder 17)
  - People for Ethnic Action and Cultural Exchange (PEACE)/McCarren Park Multi-Ethnic Festival: correspondence and printed material, 1974-76, undated (Box 135, Folder 18)
  - People's Firehouse: correspondence, flyers, clippings, newsletters, proposals, and printed material, 1978-88, undated (Box 135, Folder 19)
  - Pittsburgh Neighborhood Alliance: printed material, undated (Box 135, Folder 20)
  - Queens Women Advocates: flyer, 1980 (Box 135, Folder 21)
  - Redistribute America Movement: articles, notes, printed material, and correspondence, 1981-82, undated (Box 135, Folder 22)
  - Rural Development Leadership Network: printed material, undated (Box 135, Folder 23)
  - St. Nicholas Neighborhood Preservation and Housing Rehabilitation Corporation
    - Correspondence, 1980-87 (Box 135, Folder 24)
    - Monthly reports, 1984-85, undated (Box 135, Folder 25)
    - Annual Reports, 1979-85 (Box 136, Folder 1)
    - Housing Staff Meetings, 1984-85, undated (Box 136, Folder 2)
    - "Red Lining," undated (Box 136, Folder 3)
    - Greenline: newspapers and other materials, 1978-85, undated (Box 136, Folder 4-5)
    - Miscellaneous: notes, programs, proposals, and printed material, 1977-85, undated (Box 136, Folder 6)
  - Summer Institute in Women's History for Leaders of Women's Organizations: correspondence and printed material, 1979 (Box 136, Folder 7)
  - TRANET: correspondence and printed material, undated (Box 136, Folder 8)
  - Tucson Women's Collective: flyer, undated (Box 136, Folder 9)
  - United Tradeswomen: draft by-laws, 1983 (Box 136, Folder 10)
  - Urban Women Society, Inc: flyer, 1990 (Box 136, Folder 11)
  - Westside Women's Center: correspondence, 1986 (Box 136, Folder 12)
  - Wider Opportunities for Women, Inc.: correspondence, 1984 (Box 136, Folder 13)
  - Williamsburg Community Corporation: monthly reports, 1976 (Box 136, Folder 14)
  - Williamsburg Council of Services Agencies: correspondence, minutes, newsletters, and printed material, 1976-77, undated (Box 136, Folder 15)
  - Williamsburg-Greenpoint Community Planning Board No. 1 (City of New York)
    - General
      - Description, undated (Box 136, Folder 16)
      - Correspondence, 1985-89 (Box 136, Folder 17)
      - Board meetings, 1980-91 (Box 136, Folder 18)
      - Public hearings, 1979-88 (Box 136, Folder 19)
      - District manager, 1987-88 (Box 136, Folder 20)
      - Jan Peterson's applications for reappointment, 1985-87 (Box 136, Folder 21)
      - "Participation and representation in NYC's Community Board System" (report), undated (Box 136, Folder 22)
      - Financial: Budget committee and miscellaneous, 1984-89 (Box 136, Folder 23)
      - Miscellaneous: memoranda, printed material and lists, 1987, undated (Box 136, Folder 24)
    - Committees
      - Attendance committee: report (Box 137, Folder 1)
      - By-Laws Committee: report, by-laws, and miscellaneous (Box 137, Folder 2)
      - Education committee: correspondence (Box 137, Folder 3)
      - Greenpoint Hospital Homeless Shelter Select Committee: correspondence, resolution, and printed material, 1986-87 (Box 137, Folder 4)
      - Manhattan/Nassau Avenues Reconstruction Ad Hoc Committee (Box 137, Folder 5)
      - Parks and Recreation
        - General: correspondence, meetings, reports, notes, financial material, printed material, and miscellaneous (Box 137, Folder 6-10)
        - Projects
          - Operation Greenthumb / Street-tree planting (Box 137, Folder 11)
          - Brooklyn-Queens Expressway Reconstruction Project (Box 137, Folder 12)
          - Bushwick Pools (Box 137, Folder 13)
          - Friends of Cooper Park (Box 137, Folder 14)
          - Friends of De Diego Park (Box 137, Folder 15)
          - Father Papieluszko Square (Box 137, Folder 16)
          - Friends of La Cabana Plaza (Box 138, Folder 1)
          - Lindsay Park (Box 138, Folder 2)
          - Marcy Playground (Box 138, Folder 3)
          - Friends of McCarren Park (Box 138, Folder 4-5)
          - McGoldrick Park (Box 138, Folder 6)
          - Friends of Met Pool (Box 138, Folder 7)
          - Site 5 (Box 138, Folder 8)
          - Friends of Washington Square (Box 138, Folder 9)
          - Friends of Williamsburg Bridge Playground (Box 138, Folder 10)
          - Zindale Park (Box 138, Folder 11)
      - U.L.U.R.P. Committee: 1985-88 (Box 138, Folder 12)
      - Waterfront Committee (Box 138, Folder 13)
      - Women's Caucus (Box 138, Folder 14)
      - Youth Services Planning Committee (Box 138, Folder 15)
      - Williamsburg Coalition for Quality Housing (formerly Ad Hoc Committee for La Cabana Housing) (Box 138, Folder 16-17)
    - Area Policy Board (Box 138, Folder 18-19)
  - Williamsburg-Greenpoint Women's Political Action Alliance: correspondence, printed material, notes, photographs, meetings, mailing lists, and financial material, 1986-90 (Box 139, Folder 1-7)
  - Women, Inc.: printed material, undated (Box 139, Folder 8)
  - Women and Employment, Inc.: correspondence, mailing list, newsletter, and printed material, 1983, undated (Box 139, Folder 9)
  - Women and Mortgage Credit Project: correspondence, brochure, flyer, and printed material, 1980, undated (Box 139, Folder 10)
  - Women Employed "Salute to Working Women": program, 1978 (Box 139, Folder 11)
  - Women in Community Advocacy: manual, undated (Box 139, Folder 12)
  - Women in Crisis ("Dialogue on Pay Equity"), 1983 (Box 139, Folder 13)
  - Women of Many Voices: correspondence and mailing list, 1982-85, undated (Box 139, Folder 14)
  - Women Office Workers: printed material, undated (Box 139, Folder 15)
  - Women Pro Se, Inc.: flyers, misc., notes, poems, papers, reports, songs, and printed material, 1978-81, undated (Box 139, Folder 16)
  - Women United for a Better Chicago ("Women Safe Shelter" conference), 1986 (Box 139, Folder 17)
  - Women's Action Alliance: articles, correspondence, and notes, 1979-86, undated (Box 139, Folder 18)
    [See also National Women's Agenda Coalition; and SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment-P.O.D.]
  - Women's Development Corporation: correspondence, newsletters, memo, and printed material, 1979-80, undated (Box 140, Folder 1)
  - Women's Funding Coalition: correspondence, minutes, printed material, 1977-89 (Box 140, Folder 2-3)
    [See also New York Women's Coalition; and SERIES II. PROGRAMS-Employment-P.O.D.]
  - Women's Housing Coalition: correspondence and printed material, 1986 (Box 140, Folder 4)
  - Women's Political Caucus of Brooklyn: correspondence, flyers, reports, and printed material, 1975-84, undated (Box 140, Folder 5)
  - Women's Project & Productions: newsletter, program, and printed material, 1991, undated (Box 140, Folder 6)
  - Working Women's Forum (India): greeting card, undated (Box 140, Folder 7)
  - Youth Action Program: correspondence, 1991 (Box 140, Folder 8)
- SERIES IV. PHOTOGRAPHS circa 1970s-1990s
  - Individuals and groups (Includes Jan Peterson, Bertha Gilkey, Rosemary Jackson, Maria Rivera, and others) (Box 141, Folder 1)
  - Unidentified individuals (Box 141, Folder 2)
  - NCNW conferences and workshops
    - Alternatives for Women, NY (photos by Patricia Garrett) (Box 141, Folder 3)
    - National Training Institute (College Program conference), 1979 (Box 141, Folder 4)
    - Leadership Development and Support Training Program, 1981 (Box 141, Folder 5)
    - Neighborhood Women National leadership forum, 1982 (Box 141, Folder 6)
    - "Neighborhood Women Putting it Together": contact sheets, 1979 (Box 141, Folder 7)
  - Miscellaneous events, sites and scenes
    - CETA fight - march on Town Hall, March 7, 1980
      [See also Development-DOE, NYC]
      - Photographs (Box 141, Folder 8)
      - Contact sheets and negatives (Box 141, Folder 9)
    - Ethnic Heritage Festival (?): contact sheets and negatives, circa 1970s (Box 141, Folder 10)
    - Battered Women's Center; Carroll Gardens: contact sheets, circa 1970s (Box 141, Folder 11)
    - Neighborhood scenes and Swinging Sixties senior center: contact sheets and negatives, circa 1970s (Box 141, Folder 12)
    - You Can School graduation, 1998 (Box 141, Folder 13)
    - UN meetings with PNG, Kenya and NYC Institute/Exchange, 1999 (Box 141, Folder 14)
    - Unidentified events: contact sheets and negatives (Box 141, Folder 15)
    - Miscellaneous (Box 141, Folder 16)
  - Photographs used in NCNW publication, Neighborhood Women Putting it Together, 1980 (Box 142, Folder 1)
  - Photographs reproduced from Jan Peterson's albums
    - Album #1 includes "Brooklyn scenes, early NWWG and NCNW and family" (Box 142, Folder 2-3)
    - Album #2 includes "early international work, exchanges, and people such as Geraldine Miller, Sandy Schilen, Caroline Pezzulla, and others" (Box 142, Folder 4)
  - UNICEF, women working in Ethiopa, undated
    - Stock photographs (Box 142, Folder 5)
    - Slides and descriptions (Box 142, Folder 6)
- SERIES V. AUDIOVISUAL MATERIALS circa 1976-1990s
  - Audiocassette tapes [Research copies]
    - "Rosalie Wysoboski," interview, part 1 {Founder, Italian American Women's Council} (Box 143, Folder 1)
    - "Rosalie Wysoboski," interview, part 2 (side A) (Box 143, Folder 2)
    - "Elizabeth Sporanza," interview (side B) (Box 143)
    - "Elizabeth Sporanza's House - Film Meeting" {discussion of Ethnic Heritage film, senior citizen housing, daycare-Parent Advisory Committee, Cooper Park; cuts off on second side} (Box 143, Folder 3)
    - "Ethnic Heritage pre-production Meeting -Rosemary, Joan, Michael, Christine," 24 Feb 1979 (Box 143, Folder 4)
    - "Ethnic Heritage Pre-production Meeting" {continued} (Box 143, Folder 5)
    - "Ethnic Heritage film ideas: Land Game - Victor Menkin, 'What people have done to make their living environments better,' ethnicity ad, STARS and GRASSHOPPER, discussion of Woodstock" (side A) (Box 143, Folder 6)
    - "NCNW Board" meeting (side B) (Box 143)
    - "Film ideas / NCNW Board" (side A) (Box 143, Folder 7)
    - "NCNW Board Stuff" (side B) (Box 143)
    - "Ethnic Heritage - Cooper Park Women Tape #1" (Box 143, Folder 8)
    - "Cooper Park Meeting #2" (side A) {continuation of discussion on tape 8} (Box 143, Folder 9)
    - Discussion on leadership (side B) (Box 143)
    - "Ethnic Heritage Cooper Park - Neighborhood Conference: Women & Men, women and Community Work, Dianet-Moslem, Religion, Bordomuti Community Work, New Organization, 'What Did Community Work do for you'" (side A) (Box 143, Folder 10)
    - "Film Ideas / Conference on Neighborhoods: Sally at NCLE GOUG conference, BANNER - Italian American Demonstration, Miton Futler, Christine, Mollie Koff" (side B) (Box 143)
    - "Ethnic Heritage - Italian Women" (Box 143, Folder 11)
    - "Cooper Park Women's tape" {many faded parts} (Box 143, Folder 12)
    - Employment, 10/27 (Box 143, Folder 13)
    - original audio tapes (Box 144)
      [Please use research copies]
  - Video tapes
    - "Metropolitan Avenue" (documentary on Williamburg-Greenpoint neighborhood women), 1985 (Box 145, Folder 1)
    - "Partnership in East Harlem: James Weldon Johnson Houses and National Congress of Neighborhood Women," undated (Box 145, Folder 2)
    - "Voices from the Summit: Neighborhood Women Tell their Stories" (Oregon Women's Summit, NCNW affiliate), 1997 (Box 145, Folder 3)
    - "Working-Class Women Changing Their World": documentary by Christine Noschese (includes first NCNW national conference, 1975), 1977 (Box 145, Folder 4)
      [original footage for this documentary has been digitized and is available for viewing online]
  - Videotapes ("Helical scan" reel-to-reel)
    [NOTE: The following videos have been digitized and are available for viewing online]
    - "National Conference of Neighborhood Women Bust Trip--Speak Out"10/19/74 (Item Tape no. 1)
    - "Conference of Neighborhood Women--Rape and Welfare Discussion" 10/19/74 (Item Tape no. 2)
    - "Conference of Neighborhood Women--Organizing Discussion--G. Gincotta" 10/19/74 (Item Tape no. 3)
    - "National Conference of Neighborhood Women, Speak Out--Organizing Workshops and Peterson Tape 2" 10/19/74 (Item Tape no. 4)
    - "National Conference of Neighborhood Women, Final Reports and Church Service Tape no. 6" 10/20/74 (Item Tape no. 5)
    - "National Congress of Neighborhood Women--Why I Joined" 5/75 (Item Tape no. 6-7)
    - "Elizabeth San Filippio Class--NCNW" 7/17/75 (Item Tape no. 8)
    - "NCNW College Orientation, family, number 4" 9/17/75 (Item Tape no. 9)
    - "National Congress of Neighborhood Women (Street Visuals) II" 10/17/75 (Item Tape no. 10)
    - "Mass Transit Street Theater (preview) Tape number 3" 4/8/76 (Item Tape no. 11)
    - "Adele" 11/30/76 (Item Tape no. 12)
    - "Adele New Housing" (Item Tape no. 13)
    - "Marie Leanza at Ambulance Corps--rough cut for NCNW conference tape" 6/15/77 (Item Tape no. 14)
    - "NCNW Conference Tape--rough edit" (Item Tape no. 15)
    - "Plenary Session Tape number 1" 3/16/79 (Item Tape no. 16)
    - "NCNW Tape number 2" 3/16/79 (Item Tape no. 17)
    - "NCNW workshops tape number 3" 3/16/79 (Item Tape no. 18)
    - "NCNW Conference afternoon tape number 4" (Item Tape no. 19)
    - "NCNW Closing Remarks tape number 5" 3/16/79 (Item Tape no. 20)
    - "Leadership Training number 1--some intros" 5/10 (Item Tape no. 21)
    - "Leadership Training number 2--some role play and street life" 5/10 (Item Tape no. 22)
    - "Leadership Training number 1 SAT--But I can't afford it" (Item Tape no. 23)
    - "Leadership Training Sat, Tape 2 (about 1/2)" (Item Tape no. 24)
    - "Battered Women Tape I" (Item Tape no. 25)
    - "Battered Women 2" (Item Tape no. 26)
    - "Battered Women Tape III" (Item Tape no. 27)
    - "Number 1 Thurs. Morning" (Item Tape no. 28)
    - "Number 2 Thurs. morning--Education Conferences" (Item Tape no. 29)
    - "1-2 Thurs. Morn." (Item Tape no. 30)
    - "Number 4 Thurs. AM--Thurs. even. oral history" (Item Tape no. 31)
    - "Number 5 Thurs. eve. oral history--Education Conference" (Item Tape no. 32)
    - "Enact Conference" (Item Tape no. 33-34)
    - "Housework Conference" 10/13/77 (Item Tape no. 35-39)
    - "Housework Commercials--National Congress" (Item Tape no. 40)
    - "National Conference of Neighborhood Women--Intro" (possibly First National Conference in 1976)6/25 (Item Tape no. 41)
    - "National Congress"6/25 (Item Tape no. 42-49)
    - "National Congress of Neighborhood Women orientation" (Item Tape no. 50-51)
    - "NCNW [illegible] Tape II" 6/26 (Item Tape no. 52)
    - "Gospel Singing/community groups number 6" (Item Tape no. 53)
    - "Community groups number 9b" (Item Tape no. 54)
    - "Advocacy workshop number 8" (Item Tape no. 55)
    - "Communication, skill and power number 10" (Item Tape no. 56-57)
    - "College fair tape 1" (Item Tape no. 58)
    - "Northside Fire House" (Item Tape no. 59)
    - "EDU" 6/3 (Item Tape no. 60)
    - [unlabled-unused?] (Item Tape no. 61)
- OVERSIZED MATERIALS
  - SERIES I. ADMINISTRATION
    - National meetings: poster, 1976 (Map-case Flat file)
    - Public relations: article and NCNW newspapers - originals (copies in collection) (Map-case Flat file)
  - SERIES II. PROGRAMS
    - Housing and tenants
      - G.R.E.C.-Neighborhood Women's Inter-generational Housing project: plans (Map-case Flat file)
    - International
      - GROOTS: "GROOTS goals" (handwritten cardboard poster) (Map-case Flat file)
      - Subjects: miscellaneous posters
        - Foundation for the Support of Women's Work, Istanbul, Turkey, 1986 (Map-case Flat file)
        - Youth for Unity and Voluntary Action, Bombay, India, 1988 (Map-case Flat file)
        - People's Dialogue on Land and Shelter, Cape Town & Johannesburg, S.A., 1991 (Map-case Flat file)
        - World Habitat Day, Oct. 7, 1991 {in Spanish} (Map-case Flat file)
    - Leadership
      - National Leadership Training Forum for Neighborhood Women: poster, 1982 (Map-case Flat file)
      - Leadership Evaluation Workshop: flip chart, 1981 (Map-case Flat file)
    - Miscellaneous conferences, workshops, and events
      - Workshops: handwritten notes from flip chart for unidentified workshop, 1981 (Map-case Flat file)
      - Events: Labor Theater poster (Map-case Flat file)
  - SERIES III. ORGANIZATIONS
    - Williamsburg-Greenpoint Community Planning Board No. 1
      - Brooklyn-Queens Expressway Reconstruction Project: plans, 1987 (Map-case Flat file)
      - Friends of Cooper Park: plans (Map-case Flat file)